Newsletter Inago Issues 1980-2005
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Newsletter Inago Issues 1980-2005
MS 567
Reitz, Delford J. (Del.), 1933-2005.
This collection contains all volumes of the publication Newsletter Inago. Indexes by author name and chronological date are also included.
1.1 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/ E-Mail: LBRY-askspcoll@email.arizona.edu
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Historical Note
Newsletter Inago began in 1979 as a workshop supplement, edited and produced by Delford "Del" Reitz in Tucson, Arizona. It was a monthly poetry newsletter with a simple format, ran on low production costs, and provided a platform of exposure for poets. The newsletter was read and subscribed to nationally as well as internationally and was on many university holdings lists.
Inago is Japanese for grasshopper, singular or plural, depending upon context, for which this newsletter is named after.
Arrangement
This collection is organized chronologically by date of publication.
Scope and Content Note
Issues 1980-2005: Newsletter volumes in this collection are of letter size and span on average 5 total pages per monthly issue. Each issue begins with a brief author biography or introductory remarks. Individual poems run for less than 50 lines and author submissions are of between 10 to 15 poems each per issue. The issue header contains editor/publisher name, volume and issue numbers, month and year of publication, International Standard Serial Number (ISSN), an address to contact, as well as the title with the official grasshopper iconographic symbol. Included indexes are on 4.5 inch by 3 inch index cards, containing the header information and number of pages, and are arranged by chronological order or author name.
Access Terms
Newsletters -- Periodicals.
Poetry -- 20th century -- Periodicals.
Poetry -- 21st century -- Periodicals.
Tucson (Ariz.)
Container List
This collection is arranged chronologically by date of publication.
- Author index (1 of 2), September, 1980-December, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Author index (1 of 2), September, 1980-December, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Chronological index, September, 1980-December, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Volume 1, Number 39-Volume 2, Number 13, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Volume 2, Number 14-Volume 4, Number 8, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- First Inago Anthology of Poetry, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Volume 4, Number 9-Volume 6, Number 12, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Volume 7, Number 1-Volume 8, Number 8, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Volume 8, Number 9-Volume 10, Number 9, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Volume 10, Number 10-Volume 12, Number 6, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Volume 12, Number 7-Volume 14, Number 7, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Volume 14, Number 8-Volume 15, Number 12, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Volume 16, Number 1-Volume 18, Number 8, 1996-1998 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Volume 18, Number 9-Volume 19, Number 12, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Author index, January, 2000-July, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Chronological index, January, 2000-July, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Volume 20, Number 1-Volume 23, Number 12, 2000-2003 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Volume 24, Number 1-Volume 25, Number 10, 2004-2005 (Box 3, Folder 2)